Guide to the Allegheny Observatory Records, 1850-1977 UA.5.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Publications, 1870-1975; XIII.
  - Pamphlets, 2.
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - Calculators (Box 72, Folder 52)
      - Comparators (Box 72, Folder 53)
      - Dark Room catalogues (Box 72, Folder 54)
      - David W. Mann Company (Box 72, Folder 55-56)
      - Digitzer (Box 72, Folder 57)
      - Grant Instruments (Box 72, Folder 58)
      - Grant - Legal (Box 72, Folder 59)
      - Grant Machine - Manual (Box 72, Folder 60)
      - Hewlett-Packard 2114A Computer Manual (Box 72, Folder 61)
      - Hollow Cathode Tubes (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - Instrumentation at Astronomical Observatory (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - Keeler - Telescope (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Magnetic Counters (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Measuring Equipment (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - Measuring Systems (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Optical Equipment Brochures (Box 77, Folder 7)
      - Optical Instruments/Accessories (Box 77, Folder 8)
      - PDP Computers (Box 77, Folder 9-11)
      - Photomultiplier Tubes (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - Projection Measuring Lens correspondence (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Remote Job Entry (Box 77, Folder 14)
      - Shaded Pole Motors Blower Wheels (Box 77, Folder 15)
      - Sorbus (Box 77, Folder 16)
      - Spectrograph (Box 77, Folder 17)
      - Spitz Planetarium (Box 77, Folder 18)
      - Telescopes (Box 77, Folder 19-21)
      - Westing House Documents (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - Reprints and Scholarly Papers, 3.
    - Allegheny Reprints (Box 77, Folder 23)
      Wagman, N.E. "A Large Lens Gets a Face Lifting." 1945.
      Wagman, N.E. "Update." in from The Astronomical Journal 67, No. 9, November 1962.
      Wagman, N.E. "Update." in The Astronomical Journal 68, No. 9, November 1963.
      Wagman, N.E. "Update." in The Astronomical Journal 70, No. 9, November 1965.
      Beardsley, W.R. et al. "Photographic determinations of the parallaxes of 25 stars with the Thaw refractor." Repinted from the Astronomical Journal, Vol. 78, No. 1. February 1973.
      Beardsley, W. R. "Astrometric-Spectroscopic Techniques of Double Stars with Particular Application To γ Geminorum." Reprinted from IAU Symposium No. 30, 1967. Birkenhead: Willmer Brothers Limited, 1967.
      Bartko, Frank and R. A. Hanel. "Non-Gray Equilibrium Temperature Distributions Above the Clouds of Venus." Reprinted from The Astrophysical Journal, Vol. 151, January 1968.
      Beardsley, Wallace R. "Astrometric-Spectroscopic Triple System Mizar B." Reprinted from The Astronomical Journal 69, No. 8, October 1964.
      Vaerewyck, Eugene G. and W.R. Beardsley. "Motion of Fourteen Stars in the Orion Nebula Cluster." Reprinted from The Astrophysical Journal, No. 182, May 15 1973.
      Gatewood, George. "An astrometric study of Lalande 21185." Reprinted from The Astronomical Journal, Vol. 79, No. 1, January 1974.
      Gatewood, George and Alan L. Behall. "On the nature of the triple-star system 13 Ceti." Reprinted from The Astronomical Journal, Vol. 80, No. 12, December 1975.
      Gatewood, George and Jan Paul Dabrowski, "On the Trigonometric Parallaxes of Several Subdwarf Stars." Gatewood, George. "An Astrometric Study of Kuiper 84 (BD + 4°3562)."
      Kamper, Karl W. Jr. "Parallax and orbit for the suspected subluminous binary 2 Andromedae." Reprinted from The Astronomical Journal, Vol. 79, No. 1, January 1974.
      Kiewiet de Jonge, Joost H. "On the Relationships Between the Frequency Functions of Stellar Velocities." Reprinted from The Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 34, No.12, December 1948.
      Kiewiet de Jonge, Joost H. "Three-star Position Tables for Air Navigation." Reprinted from The Journal of the Institute of Navigation, Vol.5, No.1, January 1952.
      Kiewiet de Jonge, Joost H. "Testing A 100-inch Mirror." Written for American Optical, Date Unknown. Kiewiet de Jonge, Joost H. "Notes on the Interpretation of Astigmatic Coefficients as Derived from a Hartmann Test Analysis." Written for Owens-Illinois, January 28, 1969.
      Schlesinger, Frank. "A Simple Method for Adjusting the Polar Axis of an Equatorial Telescope." in Miscellaneous Scientific Papers of the Allegheny Observatory, Vol. 2, No. 1. Reprinted from Popular Astronomy, Northfield Minnesota, 1911.
      Lippincott, Sarah Lee and Nicholas E. Wagman. "Parallax and Orbital Motion of the Astrometric Binary α Ophiuchi from Plates Taken with the Allegheny 30 in. Thaw Refractor and the Sproul 24-in. Refractor." Reprinted from The Astronomical Journal, Vol. 71, No. 2, March 1966.
    - "Accuracy of Radial Velocities Determined with Fiber Optic Electrostatic Image Tube" (Box 77, Folder 24)
      Beardsley, W.R. et al. "Accuracy of Radial Velocities Determined with Fiber Optic Electrostatic Image Tube." Reprinted from Publications of the Allegheny Observatory of the University of Pittsburgh, Vol. 7, No. 7, 1969.
    - "Copernicus" (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - "Recording of Star Spectra with a Fiber Optic Electrostatic Image Intensifier" (Box 77, Folder 26)
      Hansen, J.R., Joost H. Kiewiet de Jonge and W.R. Beardsley. "Recording of Star Spectra with a Fiber Optic Electrostatic image Intensifier." Reprinted from Image Technology, August/September, 1969.
    - "The Astrometric Standard Region in Praesepe (M44)" (Box 77, Folder 27)
      Russell, Jane Lorene. "The Astrometric Standard Region in Praesepe (M44)." Submitted to the Graduate Faculty of Arts and Sciences in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirements for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy, University of Pittsburgh, 1976.
    - "Corrections to Observed Frequency Distributions" (Box 77, Folder 28)
      Bok, Bart J. and Joost H. Kiewiet de Jonge. "Corrections to Observed Frequency Distributions." Cambridge, Massachusetts, December 10, 1949.
    - "The Effect of a Flattened Earth on the Motion of Artificial Satellites in Near Earth Orbit" (Box 77, Folder 29)
      Stein, John W. "The Effect of a Flattened Earth on the Motion of Artificial Satellites in Near Earth Orbit." December 7, 1972.
    - "An interative technique for the rectification of observed distributions" (Box 77, Folder 30)
      Lucy, L. B. "An iterative technique for the rectification of observed distributions." Reprinted from The Astronomical Journal, Vol. 79, No. 6, June 1974.
    - "Magnetic Reversals of the Earth As Affected by its Gyrodynamical Stability" (Box 77, Folder 31)
      Allen, James B. "Magnetic Reversals of the Earth as Affected by its Gyrodynamical Stability." September 12, 1974.
    - "On the Absolute Magnitudes of the A-Type Stars" (Box 77, Folder 32)
      Kiewiet de Jonge, Joost H. "On the Absolute Magnitudes of the A-Type Stars." A Thesis Submitted in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirement for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy, Cambridge, Mass: Harvard University, May 1, 1954.
    - "On the Steady Flow of Gas From the nuclei of Seyfert Galaxies" (Box 77, Folder 33)
      Wolfe, Arthur M. "On the Steady Flow of Gas From the Nuclei of Seyfert Galaxies." Reprinted from The Astrophysical Journal, Vol. 188, No. 2, March 1, 1974.
    - "Present and Future Effects of Mercury Vapor Lighting on Astronomical Research" (Box 77, Folder 34)
      Breakiron, Lee and Jane Russell. "Present and Future Effects of Mercury Vapor Lightning on Astronomical Research." for Astronomy 232, October 1971.
    - "A Proposal to Form An Astrometric Instrument Definition Team for the Large Space Telescope" (Box 77, Folder 35)
      Beardsley, Wallace R. "A Proposal to Form an Astrometric Instrument Definition Team for the Large Space Telescope." February 23,1973.
    - "A Proposal to Survey Nearby Stars for the Perturbative Effects of Extrasolar Planetary Systems, January 1, 1976 - December 31, 1976." (Box 77, Folder 36)
      Gatewood, George D. "A Proposal to Survey Nearby Stars for the Perturbative Effects of Extrasolar Planetary Systems, January 1, 1976 - December 31,1976." July 9, 1975.
    - "Recent Research on the Third Integral of Motion" (Box 77, Folder 37)
      Zajdel, T.T. Jr. "Recent Research on the Third Integral of Motion." for Celestian Mechanics, Astronomy 218. April 6, 1971.
    - "A Summary of the Work of Percival Lowell" (Box 77, Folder 38)
      James, Hayes. "A Summary of the Work of Percival Lowell." Astronomy 218.
    - "Tidal Interactions and Spin-Orbit Coupling" (Box 77, Folder 39)
      Breakiron, Lee "Tidal Interactions and Spin-Orbit Coupling." for Celestial Mechanics, April 12, 1971.
- Correspondence (Miscellaneous), 1881-1900; XIV.
  Series XIV contains miscellaneous correspondence from the individuals at Allegheny Observatory. The (?) denotes that the author or receipiant is illegible or unknown.
  - To Prof. George Davidson, ? From J.J. Stewart Wells, Fargo Co's Express, Lone Pine, CA. Discusses Davidson's planned trip up Mt. Whitney in California, July 6, 1881 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - To ?. From B.S. Hillard, Monroeville, AL. Discusses train arrivals in Monroeville and the cost of lodging, ais, May 4, 1890
  - To ?. From ?, Clark University, Worchester, MA. Requests information on insulated wires for an article on which he is working, ALS, August 1891
  - To Penn Sharpe Manufacturing Co., ?. From?, Clark University, Worcester, MA. Requests an order for a worm, AL, October 16, 1891
  - To Harry Harrer, esquire, Allegheny Observatory. From?, Harvard College Observatory, Cambridge, MA. Informs him of his unsuccessful search for a comet about which Harrer had mentioned to him previously, ALS, September 5, 1896
  - To Frank Thompson, first vice-president, Pennsylvania Railroad, Philadelphia, from Benjamin Thaw, Pittsburgh. Letter gives historical background on Samuel Langley's work on standardized time, Photocopy, April 30, 1896
  - To Henry Harrer, Allegheny Observatory, from Hamilton Holt, editor of The Independent, New York. Request manuscript of an article by Harrer, TLS, March 24, 1900
  - To Ms. Munscher, ? from E.A. Strong, ? Discusses longitude of Grand Rapids, ALS, no date
- History, 1912-1987; XV.
  Series XV contains histories of the Allegheny Observatory. All of the known authors are listed. If the author is not listed, he/she is unknown.
  - The Allegheny Observatory of the University of Pittsburgh, [c. mid 1950s] by Theordora M. Lauterbach (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - The Allegheny Observatory, [c. mid 1910s] (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Data Relating to the History, Organization, and Activities of the Allegheny Observatory of the University of Pittsburgh, [c. 1930-37] (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Allegheny Observatory, 1958 by Lee Sellars. Also, includes a letter to Sellers from Director Wagman suggesting small changes in his manuscript. (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Allegheny Observatory of the University of Pittsburgh: Data presented for consideration if the Commission on Justifications of Higher Education, Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1952 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Pittsburgh's Eye on the Universe, Allegheny Observatory, from Equitable News, May-June, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Astronomy in Pittsburgh, from The Presbyterian Banner, September 5, 1912 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Copy of Act of Incorporation (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Copy of Deed to Observatory Land (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Speech on Observatory given by Dr. Holland, no date (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Notes on Observatory History (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Dedication of the New Observatory Building, 1912 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Program from the dedication of the new observatory (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Speech given by Chancellor McCormick at the dedication of the new observatory building (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Speech given by, ?, President of the Astronomical and Astrophysical Society of America at the dedication of the New Observatory Building (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - Invitation list for dedication (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - Invitation for dedication (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Subscription solicitation for dedication (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Romancing the Stars, by David A. Fryxell, Pitt Magazine, July 1987 (Box 73, Folder 19)
  - The Allegheny Observatory of the University of Pittsburgh, pamphlet, 1985
  - The Wandering Stars of Allegheny, by Roger Sinnot, Sky Telescope, October, 1987
- Photographs, 1886-1922; XVI.
  Series XVI contains photographic prints and negatives (mainly glass plates) of the Observatory, along with personal photography of some of the astronomers. The prints, found in Boxes 16-17, are mostly of the negatives that are part of the collection. Some of these photographs have been scanned and are available online.
  - Photographic Negatives, 1.
    - Original Allegheny Observatory
      - Exterior Views
        - Original Allegheny Observatory (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Original Allegheny Observatory building (George W. Tea, photographer: 1886) (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Old Allegheny Observatory, front view (George W. Tea, photographer: 1886) (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
        - Original Allegheny Observatory (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
      - Interior Views
        - Seat ladder from Fitz telescope (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - 13 inch refractor, Allegheny Observatory (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - 13 inch refractor (Fitz) (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - 16 inch Wolf doublet mounted on 13 inch Allegheny Observatory Equatorial (R.R.M. Thorne, photographer) (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Observations and Research
        - Sunspot drawing, S.P. Langley (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
        - List of the principal memoirs and articles on scientific research conducted at the Allegheny Observatory, 1869-1893 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Second Allegheny Observatory
      - Exterior Views
        - Keeler's proposed plan for the Allegheny Observatory (1895) (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - Proposed designs for new Allegheny Observatory (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction site preparation (R.R. M. Thorn, photographer: June 23, 1900) (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction, foundation work (R.R.M. Thorne, photographer: July 17, 1900) (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction (R.R.M. Thorne, photographer: July 17, 1900) (Box 1a, Folder 1)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction (R.R.M. Thorne, photographer, July 28, 1900) (Box 1a, Folder 2)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction, view of wall erection (R.R.M. Thorne, photographer: July 28, 1900) (Box 1a, Folder 3)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction, wall erection (R.R.M. Thorne, photographer: August 25, 1900) (Box 1a, Folder 4)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction, stone laying (R.R.M. Thorne, photographer: October 20, 1900) (Box 1a, Folder 5)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction (Box 1a, Folder 6-18)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
        - View of Allegheny Observatory before completion of domes (Box 2, Folder 4)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction front elevation (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction, general view of scaffolding (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - Allegheny Observatory construction, scaffolding (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Allegheny Observatory (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - Allegheny Observatory, front view (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - Allegheny Observatory, showing transit house, (lantern slide) (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - Front view of Allegheny Observatory (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - Front view of Allegheny Observatory, (Frank Jordan, photographer; positive image). (Box 2, Folder 12)
        - Southeast view of Observatory, (Positive image) (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - Observatory grounds (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - Observatory grounds, looking west (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
        - Path to Observatory by Keeler dome, (March 3, 1924) (Box 2, Folder 17)
        - From roof of Allegheny Observatory, looking west (Box 2, Folder 18)
        - Group on roof of Allegheny Observatory (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Interior Views
        - Hallway, Allegheny Observatory (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - Lecture hall, Allegheny Observatory (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - Director's Office, Allegheny Observatory (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
        - Library, Allegheny Observatory (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - Urania window (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - Statue of John A. Brashear (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - Allegheny Observatory shop (Box 3, Folder 8)
        - Allegheny Observatory shop, from south (Box 3, Folder 9)
        - Allegheny Observatory shop, showing part of large planer (Box 3, Folder 10)
        - Sector case and mount on dome power console (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - Worn-out 8" dome guide wheels (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Equipment
        - Porter Spectrograph (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
        - Head of Porter Spectrograph, (November 14, 1913) (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Slit of Porter Spectrograph (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Small Spectrograph and accessories (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - Infrared Spectrograph (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - Spectrograph (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - Spectrograph diagram (interferometer grating) (Box 3, Folder 20)
        - Interferometer grating spectrograph (Box 3, Folder 21)
        - Interferometer measuring attachment, (January 1929) (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - Blink comparator, from left (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - Blink comparator, from right (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Burns' comparator (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Zeiss comparator of the Allegheny Observatory (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Riefler clock (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Ordinary arc (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Vacuum arc (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - Vacuum arc, bell off (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Hilger siderostat (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Galv. Refractometer, Chas. A. Francis, U. of C. (Box 4, Folder 11)
        - "G" refractometer, Chas. A. Francis, U. of C. (Box 4, Folder 12)
        - Parallax measuring machine, (April 1, 1914) (Box 4, Folder 13)
        - Measuring engine (Box 4, Folder 14)
        - Measuring engine, from left, (April 1, 1914) (Box 4, Folder 15)
        - Long screw measuring engine (Box 4, Folder 16)
        - Gear and vernier scales of Burns' measuring engine (Box 4, Folder 17)
        - Large measuring engine, (October 13, 1926) (Box 4, Folder 18)
        - Comparison measuring engine (Box 4, Folder 19)
        - Brashear measuring engine (Box 4, Folder 20)
        - Brashear measuring engine (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - Brashear plate holder (Box 5, Folder 2)
        - Brashear device (Box 5, Folder 3)
        - Instrument: John A. Brashear Co., Ltd. (Box 5, Folder 4)
        - Instrument: John A. Brashear (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - Instrument (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
      - Thaw Telescope
        - Thaw lens on grinding table at Brashear's shop, (May 8, 1914) (Box 5, Folder 10)
        - 30" disc on grinding table, (May 8, 1914) (Box 5, Folder 11)
        - Glass discs and scrap after cutting (Box 5, Folder 12)
        - 30" disc (flint), (May 8, 1914) (Box 5, Folder 13)
        - 30" discs with cases before grinding (Box 5, Folder 14)
        - Thaw lens finished; Dr. Schlesinger and Mr. McDowell (August 3, 1914) (Box 5, Folder 15)
        - Thaw mounting construction (castings for pier made in the Rosedale Foundry machined by the Wilson Snyder Co.) (Box 5, Folder 16)
        - Thaw mounting construction; head in position (Box 5, Folder 17)
        - Thaw mounting (Box 5, Folder 18)
        - Thaw lens ready to be installed in tube (Box 5, Folder 19)
        - Thaw Telescope objective end, (July 7, 1915) (Box 5, Folder 20)
        - Thaw Telescope, (July 7, 1915) (Box 5, Folder 21)
        - Thaw Telescope (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - Thaw plate holder and eyepiece arrangement (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - 3" camera on Thaw tube (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Dr. F. C. Jordan at Thaw Telescope (Box 6, Folder 4)
        - Thaw plaque (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - Thaw Telescope (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
      - Other Telescopes
        - Transit telescope, Allegheny Observatory (Box 6, Folder 8)
        - Zenith telescope (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Observations
        - Moon (January 9, 1915) (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - Moon (January 25, 1915) (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - Moon (January 28, 1915) (Box 6, Folder 12)
        - Moon (Box 6, Folder 13-15)
        - Pleiades (December 7, 1918) (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - People Associated with the Allegheny Observatory
      - Individuals
        - Samuel P. Langley: from Scientific American, Issue of August 29, 1887 (Box 6, Folder 17)
        - Dr. Curtis (May 31, 1914) (Box 6, Folder 18)
        - Dr. Meggers (Box 6, Folder 19)
        - Mr. Daniel at the telescope. (November 14, 1920) (Box 6a, Folder 1)
        - F.C. Jordan at the telescope (November 14, 1920) (Box 6a, Folder 2)
        - F.C. Jordan at the telescope (Box 6a, Folder 3)
        - F.C. Jordan at 40" telescope (Box 6a, Folder 4)
        - Dr. Kievin Burns (Box 6a, Folder 5-7)
      - Groups
        - Group on Allegheny Observatory steps, showing Shapeley on left (Box 6a, Folder 8)
        - Steps of Allegheny Observatory: Plaskett, Eichelberger, Jordan, Schlesinger, Pickering, Brashear, Thaw, Daniels (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - Astronomical Society, group photo. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - John A. Brashear
      - Portraits
        - John A. Brashear (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - John A. Brashear (Copy: May 4, 1920) (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - John A. Brashear (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Work
        - Brashear Co. Shop (May 8, 1914) (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - Brashear's optical shop (Box 7, Folder 7)
        - 6" equatorial for Mt. Pleasant School by Brashear (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Personal Photography of Frank C. Jordan
      - Family, Friends
        - Baby, at 10 hours old (F.C. Jordan, photographer: July 19, 1898) (Box 7, Folder 9)
        - Boy and wagon (July 19, 1900) (Box 7, Folder 10)
        - Boy (May 24, 1901) (Box 7, Folder 11)
        - Boy (6:00 P.M. June 3, 1901) (Box 7, Folder 12)
        - Family group at Maplewood (1908) (Box 7, Folder 13)
        - Hattie at Picnic, Decoration Day (1909) (Box 7, Folder 14)
        - Jordan house, 49 Riverview Ave. (Box 7, Folder 15)
        - Jordan house, (north side) (Box 7, Folder 16)
        - Jordan house, (south side) (Box 7, Folder 17)
        - Jean and Andrew with snowman (1910) (Box 7, Folder 18)
        - Interior, F. Jordan dining room (J.H. Jordan, photographer) (Box 7, Folder 19)
        - Interior, F.C. Jordan parlor (J.H. Jordan, photographer) (Box 7, Folder 20)
        - Mr. And Mrs. Frank C. Jordan on porch of home (Lantern slide) (Box 7, Folder 21)
        - Group at grandfather Craig's (Box 7, Folder 22)
        - House, 49 Observatory Ave. (May 30, 1912) (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Jordan family on porch, 49 Riverview Ave. (Box 8, Folder 2)
        - F. Jordan and F.E. Vincent at 49 Observatory Ave. (August 18, 1912) (Box 8, Folder 3)
        - John William, (August 3, 1912) (Box 8, Folder 4)
        - Lightning, from rear porch, 49 Observatory Ave. (August 18, 1912) (Box 8, Folder 5)
        - F.E. Vincent, 49 Observatory Ave. (August 19, 1912) (Box 8, Folder 6)
        - John William, his dad and mama (November 28, 1912) (Box 8, Folder 7)
        - John William with father and grandfather (Box 8, Folder 8)
        - Jean in Martha Washington gown (February 22, 1913) (Box 8, Folder 9)
        - F.C. Jordan in costume (Box 8, Folder 10)
        - Hattie and F.C. in old fashioned pose (Box 8, Folder 11)
        - Campfire girls' play (Box 8, Folder 12)
        - Campfire girls, Wissahicken Hollow (Box 8, Folder 13)
        - Group at Sewickley, 706 Nevin Ave (Box 8, Folder 14)
        - A.J. Good (April 1, 1913) (Box 8, Folder 15)
        - A.J. Good and mother (April 1, 1913) (Box 8, Folder 16)
        - H.J. Heckel, Maryville picnic (June 13, 1913) (Box 8, Folder 17)
        - Jean on Observatory walk (February 25, 1914) (Box 8, Folder 18)